When I had my first company, my first agency,
I was building personal brand alongside it.
I had to shut that one
down and start a new one.
Same thing happened with the second agency.
Shut it down, the third business,
I was able to scale the multiple seven figures
within like six months because I had the personal brand.
It even helped me start my
third or my fourth business now.
And we're already at a seven figure runway
with that within 60 days.
Welcome back to episode six
of 10 Questions with Millionaires.
I'm Josh, I'm here with Robert Miller.
Robert Miller is a entrepreneur,
investor, and multimillionaire.
Robert, it's so good to meet with you today.
If you wouldn't mind, could you just give us
a quick intro on your
background and what you do today?
Yeah, sure thing.
Been in the digital marketing space,
been in the e-commerce space,
and been in the crypto space
essentially since I was 17, 18.
Got into crypto when I was in high school.
So 2015, 2016, caught it there
and have rode that wave
for the past five, six years,
but then also done a lot
of marketing for big name brands
as well as for entrepreneurs and other businesses.
What did you do after high school?
And do you think college is necessary
to be successful today?
So I went into college actually out of high school
with a friend of mine.
I was really just studying business administration,
economics, and I was very just entrepreneur driven.
So the school system for me didn't necessarily fit
even what my identified career path was gonna be.
I didn't find out what I was gonna do
until I took a course outside of college,
which was digital marketing,
Tai Lopez's first marketing course.
Because I had made some
money in crypto prior to that,
but it's not cashflow, it's just capital gains.
So when that happened, I then realized,
all right, I need to
figure out how to build cashflow,
how to build a real business.
And so I don't think that it's necessary
if you're gonna go into the entrepreneurship field
to do that.
I think it's necessary for things
that need pedigree, doctors, lawyers, et cetera.
I think everyone kind of has that same opinion,
but for business, you don't necessarily need it.
You just need to solve problems.
What advice would you give to people
who are looking to scale their business?
You have to learn how to master marketing
and bring more revenue in.
It's not just a paid ad.
It's typically mainly the content,
the actual traffic strategy.
So Facebook, TikTok, Instagram, YouTube,
like actually getting people to actually care
about what you say, what you do.
And then from there, I think it's then sales.
If you're bad at sales, have a bunch of leads,
you're gonna get something.
And then if you're great at sales
and then great at marketing,
you can grow really quick.
So I would say get good at sales.
And then the third one is a little bit unconventional,
which would be finance.
Understanding how your cash flows work.
What would you say is the top three books
that you'd recommend everyone should read?
For scaling out their business,
I would say The Road Less Stupid
gives you the mental frameworks of what to think about,
how to think about, and what to think about,
about thinking about, about thinking about.
So it helps you kind of think ahead
about rolling out a new product, a new offer.
It gives you the mental frameworks,
at least for me it did,
to just look through business.
It's at a different way
instead of it just being the expert,
the subject matter expert, the marketer,
or the tactical person.
It's actually like the strategy behind it
and how you're gonna hold people accountable to it.
Second book that I would
read if you're building a team,
it's called Multipliers,
essentially how to work with other people,
how to multiply their efforts and their goals,
align their interests.
Third book that I read that I think is,
again, really important for businesses
is called Predictable Revenue,
The $100 Million Best Practices of Salesforce
by Aaron Ross.
That one goes over different types of sales,
different types of marketing,
but how to grow and scale out a sales team.
That's really just,
to bring revenue in the door.
It's not necessarily to fulfill on product
or anything like that.
What do you feel like is the importance
of building your personal brand as a business owner?
It's extremely important
because that's all you have.
Your mechanism of what you do for people
is always gonna change
because the market changes.
Businesses don't typically last forever
unless they're financial services businesses
that then become institutions and get passed down.
And so I think if
you're in a business like marketing,
like e-commerce or anything like that,
your mechanism, your offer,
the way that you get more sales
is always gonna change.
Your personal brand's not going anywhere.
When I had my first company,
my first agency,
I was building personal brand alongside it.
I had to shut that one
down and start a new one.
Same thing happened with the second agency
because we had too many partners.
It wasn't the right fit.
Shut it down.
The third business,
I was able to scale the multiple seven figures
within like six months
because I had the personal brand.
I've been building reputation and will
in the marketplace for a while
around digital marketing
and acquisition of clients and stuff.
It even helped me start my third
or my fourth business now.
And we're already at a seven figure runway
with that within 60 days.
You've built multiple companies.
Not every single one has worked out.
What would you say to people,
on how they should approach failure?
You only need about two to three people max
in a partnership or in a company.
You don't need four to five.
I learned that lesson.
But I remember the loyalty,
obviously that was built between,
you know, the partners that I had
and everything was still strong.
You know, I couldn't have done it by myself.
A lot of people get caught up in,
like I came up with this.
So this part is so valuable to the company.
Like name doesn't mean anything
or the offer doesn't mean anything
unless it's executed on.
And so having great executional partners,
my side executing,
their side executing,
like that's been really the biggest thing
when it comes to failures.
If you can set aside your ego,
your pride and the identity of what you found
in that prior venture,
then you can actually start to see things
for what they really are
rather than your own perception of what they are
based off of your relative experience.
That comes from investing into typically events
and masterminds to get that exposure.
But I think it's having
a great team behind you, man.
I can't do it all by myself.
And it also comes down to just that loyalty
and what you build.
And what qualities should people look for
in a business partner?
You know, I've had many partnerships.
The first one, actually,
we were both just starting out in the space.
Completely brand new.
Didn't know anything about anything.
You know, second one just brought to the table
what I was lacking,
which was essentially a lot of optimism
because I had literally gone through the ringer
with previous partnerships.
I had also learned how to fail
in some campaigns and stuff like that.
And so I was kind of depleted
and I just had a very realistic,
almost sometimes even a pessimistic view.
And so I had an optimist partner
and things balanced out and worked out.
And the next group was a lot of, you know,
executors and people that had their own visions
for where they wanted to go
and a lot of entrepreneurs,
which could be good,
but also could be bad.
And I realized going through all of those,
you need to have partners
that are essentially crucial to the business,
but that won't hold it captive.
So you got to bring something to the table,
whether that's, you know, connections,
people, capital, execution, network,
something that is actually crucial
to the business function,
not just because I like you,
but then also being with someone
that you actually have the same values
and align with.
And I know that sounds really corny,
but in those times of struggle
or in those times when there
is a hiccup in the business,
if you're not aligned on core values
and the function of like,
hey, here's what we believe
and here's where we want to go.
It'll fall apart.
The core function is where are we going?
What are you bringing to the table?
What am I bringing to the table?
Let's execute, come back.
Have a real conversation.
If you're slacking off, I'm slacking off.
Call you out on your shit.
Call me out on my shit.
Let's grow.
We have a common vision and purpose.
And the whole point is to, you know,
not just to make more money,
just to have more money.
Like the other day,
I was able to give my mom a thousand bucks
because she needed it.
And that was just because
I was able to give it to her.
And so I shared that with my partner.
He's like, dude, that's freaking awesome.
Set aside business for a sec.
Like that's what it's all about.
So what are your thoughts on cryptocurrency?
Crypto is big, man.
I got into it pretty early.
It's evolved over the past like five, six years,
but it's definitely big.
And it's a lot bigger than people think.
It's not just a new tech.
It's actually a new way to even think about money.
And it's not just the Bitcoin conversation
or the Ethereum conversation.
It's a lot to do with the central banks,
essentially how they're going to monitor us with CBDCs.
Ultimately, where should we even store wealth?
What do we as society see as valuable?
Do we see something as value
as simply just something that, you know, is rare?
Or do we actually have to
have a cost associated with it?
So the Bitcoin example,
is, you know, you have to have a mining facility
in order to verify transactions.
It has actual physical costs,
physical electricity presence
in order to actually verify the transaction
with those machines.
So as a society, if we view energy
backing that specific currency
or that specific valuable item,
like a gold bar or whatever,
it has to be mined.
There's actual energy costs getting that gold bar.
Same thing for crypto.
We value energy going into something
that has scarce value.
Do we then transact with that?
Or do we just hold that and preserve it?
And does that actually change the way
that we operate with our size of ID?
Who knows?
We'll find out.
It's actually changing a lot of things now,
but I think we'll see what 3.0 looks like
and ultimately what the CBDC rollout looks like.
What got you into it?
I got started in about 2015, 2016.
My brother and I,
we were back in my hometown, Simi Valley,
and there was a guy
who was really into the dark web stuff.
And he wasn't like buying anything illegal or anything.
He was just like really into this whole concept.
And he was really early on in RuneScape.
So he had like 1500 Bitcoins
the first time that we were talking to him.
And he kind of just shared
more and more information about it.
And then he had about 15,000 Bitcoins.
And then over a course of another year or two,
he had amassed in that wallet address,
like the transactions that had gone through it,
about 150,000 Bitcoins
that had gone through that address.
Then when we saw Bitcoin hit a thousand,
we're like, oh my God,
this guy just made a bunch of money
on these digital coins.
What is it?
So I got into Bitcoin around
like 800 to a thousand bucks.
Ethereum was like $17.
Ripple was around,
but AntShares converted into Neo.
And that was a really big
project that I had come up on.
I only had a little bit of money.
I invested like 1500 bucks,
maybe two grand into the whole deal.
And literally within like four months,
that transformed into like 250 grand.
I was like,
what the heck?
Did I do that?
I just do.
I'm like 19 years old.
I'm in college.
I was like, I got to share this with people.
So I just created books and courses
and all that kind of stuff.
I was giving out for free,
was speaking on stages on it.
And then that's how I really got into cryptocurrency.
Was that your first big financial break,
would you say?
Oh, for sure.
Before then, dude, I was doing e-com.
I was doing marketing agency,
but my market was very blue collar-esque.
Like entrepreneurship was not around
in the sense of digital.
For me, I was like a scrawny kid,
just knew and loved tech.
Like it just clicked.
And I went down the rabbit hole
within three months, knew a lot.
So when I was like explaining it to people
and sharing it,
like there was just an innate draw to me
because I had this info.
And that wasn't necessarily an ego thing,
but it was like, dude,
I finally like helping people.
Like, is this what entrepreneurship is?
Like being able to help someone learn something
or teach someone something.
What would you say has been the worst
financial decision you've ever made?
I've made many, man.
I've made many.
I'm not perfect,
but this is where I really found out
who was committed to the business
and who wasn't
and whether the business was going to last.
I had actually taken out
because we had a lot of holds
with payment processors
and all this kind of stuff.
Essentially like an implosion
on payment processing.
That one month,
I had taken out like a flash loan
essentially for that payroll coverage.
It wasn't that the,
that was the wrong decision.
It was the decision that I had done that
and no one else in that same company
vouched for it or wanted to pitch into it.
I was like, that's messed up
because I'm taking out the loan
to help you guys out
when I'm trying to push the company.
I'm actually just paying your payrolls.
I just took a loan out to pay you guys.
That's not the right thing to do.
Financially, it didn't make sense
once things unraveled.
Able to pay it off.
That wasn't really a problem.
It was paid off in like a month or whatever,
but they really expose
a lot of partnerships in business.
You should never want to take out loans
or to do certain things like that.
It was just a one-time occurrence,
but that was probably the baddest,
the worst financial decision that I made,
but it actually exposed a lot more
and who is real and who isn't.
Show people who is really invested into it
and who wasn't.
Yeah, I wouldn't recommend
that be the way you find out.
It was not necessarily the most efficient way
to really weed out who's your friend
or who's not
or who's actually committed or who's not,
but you know,
that happens part of entrepreneurship.
What would you say
is the best financial decision
you've ever made?
So after I had made the money in crypto,
I had actually invested
the rest of it into courses.
So I'm a big believer in education
and like you can never really
go bankrupt on yourself
because if you give up,
that's how you go bankrupt on it, right?
I invested like 30 to 40 grand into courses.
I learned stocks.
I learned e-com.
I learned marketing.
So I became a little bit more versatile
understanding subjects.
I didn't become an expert
in every single one.
I don't think that's actually viable.
I think you should stick to one thing primarily,
but then maybe two to three things
that you are very passionate about
outside of that.
But for me, at least,
it was investing to myself.
That was probably the biggest
lump sum investment I had made.
And that was really just kind of discovering
what I wanted to do.
Flash forward as the business started
gaining more and more traction
because I had better skill sets
and our team was making more money and stuff.
I then invested into another mentorship
and other mentorship.
And I've never had an ego
around not knowing something.
In fact, I've probably invested a lot more
into just trying to find the answer
than just to go through self-discovery
to figure it out
because I'm trying to condense time.
And I think that's also a personal thing for me.
I'll bet on myself
because I know the skill sets
in every single mastermind
or every single program I've joined
has had a return.
It just clicks at a different point.
And so it's that exponential effect
where maybe the last mastermind you joined
was the catalyst for you to go
from a million dollars
to seven million in revenues.
But it was all the things that you did before,
but that was the catalyst
because that was the last link
or that was the last connection that you needed
or whatever the case is.
What has been the greatest lesson
you've learned so far?
Relationships really matter,
but the right relationships matter the most.
You can be friends to many,
but who are you going to call
in the situation
where you only have three numbers to dial?
Like if you really was,
if it was life or death,
you had three numbers to dial,
who's going to be there for you?
I think that matters the most, dude.
It's like those core relationships,
they take investment in time, money,
helping them get to where they want to go.
It's not just all about you.
I think investing into your health is key.
I've gone the full burnout way
where you're working 16 hours a day.
I actually had a really crazy health scenario
that had happened
when I was doing full-time work
and school at the time.
It was like 4 a.m. to midnight.
And then I had the next day
where I pulled an overnighter
for a government project.
We were putting a bid on a building in Pasadena.
And then I went back to school
and then went back to work.
I didn't sleep that 24, 48.
So it was pretty brutal.
And that night I had gone home,
passed out apparently,
and I was screaming at the top of my lungs
and all my books,
everything was falling off,
like the shelves and everything.
My mom came in and she was like,
what the hell is going on?
I didn't know what was going on.
So health is very, very serious.
I was stressed out to the max at the time.
I even had a girlfriend at the time.
So I had no time for anything.
And I've really learned to focus on health
and go push yourself.
What would you say is your long-term goal for yourself
and what motivates you to keep going?
Let's start with the why first
because it doesn't matter what I want to do
if I don't have a driving force to get there.
I came from a place
I came from a spot in which,
you know, my mom was
making 30, 40 grand a year
and living in the suburb of Los Angeles.
Didn't have food a lot of the times.
Just grew up always having a thirst for entrepreneurship
and was literally hungry at points.
And I was like,
I don't want to ever do that for my family.
Like we're going to be successful.
We're going to, you know,
have an abundance of food,
have an abundance of all this stuff.
Not in a gluttonous way,
but just you'll never have lack of like basic needs.
So that was the first thing.
But your why evolves as you change
because I can eat.
I just had a chef come over yesterday.
She made all my stuff because I hate cooking.
The why isn't food anymore.
The why,
it's the sustain and become a different version of myself
that I know that I can become.
And so chasing potential,
your human potential of impact,
your human potential of changing an industry
or the way that things are done,
your impact and even how you show up,
how your presence is actually felt,
I think is also another thing
a lot of people don't talk about.
Like, how do you want to
be able to walk this earth?
Are you going to be, you know,
moping around not being, you know,
the guy or the guy that can protect or provide?
Like, I think for me,
especially over the past six months,
I want to be multifaceted
and not just be the business guy.
If I can lift more,
if I can go, you know,
do a self-defense martial arts
or if I can go do X, Y, Z,
then why would I not, right?
So that's one.
It's chasing that potential
and diversifying identity.
But then the distinct why of like,
but for me, it's for my mom, for my family.
And then there's the outward facing,
where I know I can impact people.
By doing that impact,
I know that I can take care of my mom.
She's 66 years old or 65 years old.
She retires in a year.
She needed a little bit of help,
sent her some money and she was good.
And that to me is like me accomplishing
that fulfilling prophecy
where they invested into me a lot
and they had nothing.
I can at least give her a couple thousand bucks
or whatever it was to help her.
That's goals, right?
Right there, man.
That wraps up episode six
of 10 questions with a millionaire.
Thank you so much, Robert.
I appreciate you filming with us today.
Where can people find more about you
and connect with you?
Yeah, sure thing.
They can find me on Instagram.
Appreciate you having me
at the Robert J. Miller, the one and only.
So the Robert J. Miller on Instagram.
Just hit me there and I'll get back to you.